[Music]
hey welcome back to the joe walsh so we
start with an important and serious
question our intelligence community when
is it appropriate to criticize them and
how do we go about doing that we'll get
an insider's view answer to that
question in a moment then great news a
British baby is alive thanks to America
and as always we close with our gallery
of the stupid San Francisco in London
man they stand out today this issue of
our intelligence community the men and
women of the FBI and all the other
agents who are pledged to help keep us
safe in this country and around the
world it's become a big issue ever since
the election of Donald Trump it's become
a big issue because the election of 2016
made clear a very hotly contested
election made clear a couple truths that
we now know Russia interfered and there
are certainly questions about how our
very own FBI and our very own Justice
Department behaved during that campaign
questions that demand answers questions
that demand an investigation and like a
broken record I've said from the very
beginning look into both drill down on
exactly what a foreign government did to
impact our election so that that will
never happen again but don't stop there
find out exactly what our FBI did was
their bias at the FBI bias among how
many individuals bias that actually
might have impacted the election result
that needs to be looked into as well now
unfortunately 18 months later there's a
divide in the country we've got one
investigation going really strong the
Muller investigation looking into what
Rush
she did and looking into the possibility
only the possibility of any American
assisting Russia but you know what the
issue of what did our own people do were
our own people biased against Donald
Trump it's clear right it's clear that
Russia was more favorably disposed to
the president but were folks in our
government were folks in our FBI and our
Justice Department did they wait the
scales toward Hillary Clinton and
against President Trump and
unfortunately that that question has not
brought forth its own Special Counsel
and it should and it should we've had
the Inspector General look into how the
FBI behaved when it came to Hillary's
email server problem we have the FBI's
IG looking into how they handled their
role in the Russia investigation in the
Russia interference but no it's a big
enough deal this issue of what our own
people did of what our intelligence
community did I've said from the start
to help heal a divided country it
demands its own special standalone
investigation the FBI needs to be looked
at by an outside party the CIA the
Justice Department our entire
intelligence community needs a thorough
outside investigation because here's
what's going to happen you and I know
what's gonna happen Bob Muller is going
to come down with his results his
findings maybe tomorrow maybe three or
four months from now maybe nine months
from now who knows when but eventually
Robert Muller's findings on what Russia
did and did any American assist Russia
they're going to be out there for the
entire country to see and if we've only
got that story if we've only got that
part of the story and not a clear
understanding of what our
and intelligence community did this
country is going to remain very very
divided let's talk about our
intelligence community I'm very happy to
be joined by John Keary Cao John I hope
I got your last name right a former CIA
whistleblower
start with where are I let off the
entire issue John of our intelligence
community it seems to me like we need a
thorough investigation into their
behavior wouldn't you agree without any
question I think you are absolutely
correct and this is a big problem in
Congress on Capitol Hill we have these
oversight committees that really don't
oversee anything they act more as
cheerleaders for the intelligence
community than they do as overseers and
when when you've got you know two peas
in the same pod you end up with an
intelligence community that literally
does anything it wants to do with
impunity and we've seen them try to do
exactly that for the last 18 months
so John from your very unique
perspective and we've got Americans all
over the country listening to you and I
right now watching us what is the
biggest problem that you see right now
inside our intelligence community
it's politicization to tell you the
truth Barack Obama politicized the
intelligence community unlike any other
president in in modern American history
when I first joined the CIA I genuinely
didn't know the political affiliation of
any of my colleagues because politics
never came up we never discussed it it
was never important we were there to
serve the country and that was it when
Barack Obama became president and then
especially when John Brennan became the
director of the CIA it became a very
very political organization and now you
have a situation where not just John
Brennan but three and four levels of
people below him have left the agency
and they've gone on to the to the
networks to be talking heads
I mean how political is that that's just
unprecedented it never happened in the
past and so it's going to take a lot of
hard work and a lot of congressional
over
site to go back to that nonpartisan
organization that it used to be John
most Americans want to believe look
there's bias everywhere everybody in
government has bias but like you all the
other professionals at the CIA and the
FBI they put their bias away when they
go to work every day but how true is
that you know it used to be true it used
to be the status quo and now it's
different the problem is there are so
many people at the CIA in the senior
intelligence service that's the
leadership level the executive level of
the CIA who have been there for twenty
twenty-five thirty years maybe more and
they know that if they don't like a
president or his politics they can wait
that President out they did it with
Jimmy Carter they did it with with Bill
Clinton and if they don't like Donald
Trump they think that they can wait him
out because presidents come and go and
they're always there and I think that's
really what the strategy is for a lot of
the people in the mid to higher levels
of CIA leadership this is John this is
scary stuff how how do you even begin to
fix this what Ronald Reagan did was he
fired a lot of people and I think that
there has to be a housecleaning at the
CIA again Congress should have been on
this like white on rice and they haven't
been and so what we need really is an
outside director someone who has close
personal ties with the president but not
close personal ties with the CIA
leadership to go in and clean house it's
happened a couple of times in the last
generation or two and it needs to happen
again
the current director Gina Hoffs bill
clearly that's not that's not gonna be
her role at all correct no not at all
Gina's a longtime 32-year CIA veteran
she's very very popular among the
rank-and-file she was a terrific officer
I worked directly for her when I was in
the sent the counterterrorism center but
Gina's not the kind of person is going
to make waves not at all what's what
John what's the more
if you had to guess and maybe it's more
of a guess what's the morale like among
the rank and file in our CIA
well post 9/11 morale was higher than it
had been in in recorded memory at the
CIA that's changed and it's because I
think that so many CIA officers at the
senior level have found that they can't
control Donald Trump they're so used to
being able to go into an oval office
meeting and tell the president what they
want him to do and they couch it in such
a way that they offer it up as analysis
so they suggest to the president what
they want him to do visa vie a policy
that's not the way Donald Trump does
business and so I think that it's it's
been very difficult for them to get used
to that to get used to his his
leadership style and the fact that he is
not easily ordered around and as a
result morale has dropped interesting
hey John I really appreciate your time
very interesting perspective thank you
so much for joining me
a socialized medicine kills thank God
for America I'll explain next
[Music]